<codelist name="GeographicalPrecision" xml:lang="en" complete="1" embedded="0">
    <metadata>
        <name>
            <narrative>Geographical Precision</narrative>
        </name>
        <description>
            <narrative>A system for clarifying the accuracy and usage of geographical coordinates </narrative>
        </description>
        <category>
            <narrative>Non-Core</narrative>
        </category>
    </metadata>
    <codelist-items>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>1</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Exact location</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Lieu précis</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>The coordinates corresponds to an exact location, such as a populated place or a hill. The code is also used for locations that join a location which is a line (such as a road or railroad). Lines are not coded only the points that connect lines. All points that are mentioned in the source are coded.</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Les coordonnées correspondent à un lieu précis, comme un endroit peuplé ou une colline. Le code est aussi utilisé pour les lieux qui rejoignent un autre endroit et qui est linéaire (comme une route ou une voie ferrée). Les lignes ne sont pas codées, seulement les points qui les forment. Tous les points mentionnés dans la source sont codés.</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>2</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Near exact location</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Près d'un lieu précis</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>The location is mentioned in the source as being "near", in the "area" of, or up to 25 km away from an exact location. The coordinates refer to that adjacent, exact, location.</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Le lieu est mentionné dans la source comme étant « près », dans le « secteur » ou se trouvant à jusqu'à 25 km d'un lieu précis. Les coordonnées renvoient à ce lieu précis adjacent.</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>3</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Second order administrative division</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Division administrative de second niveau</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>The location is, or lies in, a second order administrative division (ADM2), such as a district, municipality or commune</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Le lieu est ou se trouve dans une division administrative de second niveau (ADM2), comme un district, une municipalité ou une commune.</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>4</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>First order administrative division</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Division administrative de premier niveau</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>The location is, or lies in, a first order administrative division (ADM1), such as a province, state or governorate.</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Le lien est ou se trouve dans une division administrative de premier niveau (ADM1), comme une province, un État ou un gouvernorat.</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>5</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Estimated coordinates</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Coordonnées estimées</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>The location can only be related to estimated coordinates, such as when a location lies between populated places; along rivers, roads and borders; more than 25 km away from a specific location; or when sources refer to parts of a country greater than ADM1 (e.g. "northern Uganda").</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">On ne peut désigner le lieu qu'au moyen de coordonnées estimées, par exemple pour un lieu situé entre deux endroits peuplés.</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>6</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Independent political entity</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Entité politique autonome</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>The location can only be related to an independent political entity, meaning the pair of coordinates that represent a country.</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">On ne peut désigner le lieu que par rapport à une entité politique autonome, ce qui signifie la paire de coordonnées représentant un pays.</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>7</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Unclear - capital</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Imprécis - Capitale</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>Unclear. The capital is assumed to be one of two possible locations. (The other option is the country level, with precision 9.)</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Imprécis. On suppose que la capitale est l'un de deux lieux possibles. (L'autre possibilité est le niveau du pays, avec la précision 9.)</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>8</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Local or national capital</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Capitale locale ou nationale</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>The location is estimated to be a seat of an administrative division (local capital) or the national capital. If aid goes to Luanda without further specification on the location, and there is an ADM1 and a capital called Luanda, then code the coordinates of the capital with precision 8. If it is not spelled out that aid goes to the capital; but if it is clear that it goes to a government ministry or to government financial institutions; and if those institutions are most likely located in the capital; then the coordinates of the capital are coded with precision 8. (However, if it can be verified that the recipient institution is located in the capital then precision 1 is used.)</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">On estime que le lieu est le siège d'une division administrative (capitale locale) ou la capitale nationale. Si de l'aide est dirigée vers Luanda sans autre précision sur le lieu et qu'il existe une ADM1 et une capitale nommée Luanda, les coordonnées de la capitale doivent être inscrites avec la précision 8. En l'absence d'indication que l'aide va à la capitale</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>9</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Unclear - country</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Imprécis - Pays</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>Unclear. The locations is estimated to be the country level (often paired with the capital, with precision 7)</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Imprécis. On estime que lieu est un pays (accompagne souvent la capitale, avec la précision 7)</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
    </codelist-items>
</codelist>
