<codelist name="ResultType" xml:lang="en" complete="1" embedded="0">
    <metadata>
        <name>
            <narrative>Result Type</narrative>
        </name>
        <category>
            <narrative>Non-Core</narrative>
        </category>
    </metadata>
    <codelist-items>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>1</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Output</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Extrant</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>Results of the activity that came about as a direct effect of your work and specific, what is done, and what communities are reached. For example, X number of individuals.</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Résultats de l'activité découlant directement de votre travail et précisions connexes (ce qui est fait, les communautés rejointes). Par exemple, X nombre de personnes.</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>2</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Outcome</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Effet</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>Results of the activity that produce an effect on the overall communities or issues you serve. For example lower rate of infection after a vaccination programme.</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Les résultats de l'activité qui produisent un effet sur les communautés générales ou les grands enjeux sur lesquels vous intervenez. Par exemple, taux d'infection réduit après une campagne de vaccination.</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>3</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Impact</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Impact</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>The long term effects of the outcomes, that lead to larger, over arching results, such as improved life-expectancy.</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Les incidences à long terme des effets qui mènent à des résultats de niveau supérieur et de grande envergure, comme une amélioration de l'espérance de vie.</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>9</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Other</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Autre</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>Another type of result, not specified above.</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Autre type de résultat non décrit ci-dessus.</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
    </codelist-items>
</codelist>
