<codelist name="TiedStatus" xml:lang="en" complete="1" embedded="0">
    <metadata>
        <name>
            <narrative>Tied Status</narrative>
            <narrative xml:lang="fr">Condition de l’aide</narrative>
        </name>
        <category>
            <narrative>Non-Core</narrative>
        </category>
    </metadata>
    <codelist-items>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>3</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Partially tied</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Semi-conditionnelle</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>Official Development Assistance for which the associated goods and services must be procured from a restricted number of countries, which must however include substantially all aid recipient countries and can include the donor country.</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Aide publique au développement dont les biens et services correspondants doivent être achetés dans un nombre restreint de pays, qui doivent toutefois comprendre tous les pays bénéficiaires de l’aide et éventuellement le pays donateur.</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>4</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Tied</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Conditionnelle</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>Official grants or loans where procurement of the goods or services involved is limited to the donor country or to a group of countries which does not include substantially all aid recipient countries.</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Subventions ou prêts officiels dont les dispositions indiquent que les biens ou services associés ne peuvent provenir que du pays donateur ou d’un groupe de pays qui ne comprend pas nécessairement tous les pays bénéficiaires de l’aide.</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
        <codelist-item>
            <code>5</code>
            <name>
                <narrative>Untied</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Sans condition</narrative>
            </name>
            <description>
                <narrative>Untied aid is defined as loans and grants whose proceeds are fully and freely available to finance procurement from all OECD countries and substantially all developing countries.</narrative>
                <narrative xml:lang="fr">Subventions et prêts pouvant être librement et intégralement utilisés pour financer les approvisionnements auprès de tous les pays de l’OCDE et de la plupart des pays en développement.</narrative>
            </description>
        </codelist-item>
    </codelist-items>
</codelist>
